Andrew Baxter

Full-Stack Web Developer

Phone: 317-446-1938

Email: asbaxter1@gmail.com

Site: https://asbaxter.github.io/portfolio-site/
GitHub: https://github.com/asbaxter

Profile

Full stack web developer who also has over four years of management experience. At my current company I have progressed rapidly through multiple departments, proving time and time again my abilities to lead an effective team, adapt to change, and solve problems. I bring professionalism, integrity, and work ethic to everything I do and can make a positive impact on any team.

Skills

HTML	Node.js	GraphQL	Git
CSS	Express.js	REST APIs	Bootstrap
JavaScript	MySQL	React	Materialize
Python	MongoDB	MERN	Tailwind

Professional Experience

FedEx Ground / Data Analyst / May 2022 - Present

Write detailed service reports that have been able to identify and correct multiple failing processes within our station. Using these service recaps, we identified a way to reduce our miscellaneous delivery failures by around 7% by removing outdated sort rules that impacted package sortation.

FedEx Ground / Sort Manager / Oct 2021 – May 2022

Responsible for maintaining the day-to-day operations of one of the most successful FedEx facilities in the world. Lead hundreds of employees by creating a culture of safety, efficiency, and integrity. Responsible for the quality and timely delivery of tens of thousands of costumer packages daily.

FedEx Ground / Area Manager / Jan 2021 – Oct 2021

- Developed and trained operations managers to run efficient and well-organized areas, while maintaining company values and quality metrics.
- Increased weekend sort efficiency by about 10% by reengineering destinations to a more consolidated area, reducing sort times and total labor hours.

FedEx Ground / Operations Manager / Dec 2018 – Jan 2021

- Successfully lead multiple teams of package handlers through different areas of the operation.
- Reduced our controllable rehandle percentage by 50% using root cause analysis and trend tracking to better position and train facers (Jam Breakers)

We Do Windows / Field Supervisor / May 2018 – Feb 2020

Lead a team of window washers who gave hundreds of customers professional, high quality window washing experience.

Education

Butler Executive Education (May 2022 – Nov 2022)

Full Stack Web Development

Ball State University (2014 – 2018)

100 credit hours completed towards, major in criminal justice and a minor in digital forensics